João Rebelo Pinto

joaorebelopinto@gmail.com | +44 (0) 7472 902 530 | www.linkedin.com/in/joaorebelopinto

Professional Summary

Over 11 years of experience in the Media industry (with a focus on post-production and digital file distribution). History of high standards and clear communication, leading to efficient results. Transitioning careers from an account management role and seeking a full-time role in the field of data analytics.

Skills, Expertise & Languages

Skills & Experience

- ✓ Excel / Spreadsheets
- ✓ SQL
- ✓ R / Python
- ✓ Tableau

- ✓ DBT
- ✓ Snowflake
- ✓ AWS

Languages

- English (native)
- Portuguese (native)
- Spanish (basic)

Education

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate

Certification complete, currently creating a Capstone Project as a case study.

Universidade Lusófona de Humanidades e Tecnologias

Bachelor's degree in Cinema, Video and Multimedia Communication.

Employment History

Deluxe Entertainment Services (London, England)

• Account Manager - Trailer Marketing (February 2020 - Present)

Orchestrated trailer campaigns from inception to final delivery, delivering ~350 files per campaign to stakeholders.

- Heavily contributed towards workflow optimization by updating templates, aligning teams, and stakeholders.
- Headed daily communication with external stakeholders, organization and managing of internal teams, and delegating/handling the creation, distribution, and billing for trailer marketing campaigns.
- Ensured that the technical and creative requirements were continually met, and delivered products to the stakeholders on time with an average success of 98% (measured by the amount of files that were either not delivered on time or required re-delivery after deadline).

• Producer - Night Shift (February 2019 - February 2020)

Coordinated deliveries of DCPs with overnight turnaround timelines, as well as Quality Control of localized assets.

- Organized the reception of assets, DCP creation, and next-day client screening of final DCP with 12-hour turnaround timelines. Creative problem-solving skills were essential for this role since all other stakeholders were sleeping during my work hours, forcing me to think creatively and find solutions independently.
- Ensured that localized assets created by the DFX department were accurate according to stakeholders' wishes, and compliant with the highest standards through rigorous Quality Control, with an accuracy of 95% (measured by the amount files that needed to be re-rendered due to a mistake that I did not catch).

• Quality Control Operator – Features (February 2017 – February 2019)

Managed the QC team and conducted Quality Control of feature DCPs.

- QC'd a wide variety of DCP files, by flagging relevant errors like dead pixels in a single frame or audio corruptions in a track channel. These jobs included subtitled, dubbed, 2D, 3D, 5.1, 7.1, Atmos, and other varieties of DCP files.
- Maintained a near-impeccable track record with an error rate of less than 1% (measured by the amount of delivered DCPs that were found to contain a mistake after they had been QC'd and approved by me).

• Digital Cinema Technical Operator - Features (May 2016 - February 2017)

Prepared source assets and coordinated the creation of DCP files.

Organized and created a wide variety of DCPs, from simple subbed VF DCPs to complex Censor Cuts with creative input. Specs for this varied according to different requirements of high-profile stakeholders.